翻译   肉松
翻译   盐湖凉开水
翻译   苏小黛
翻译   国士章鱼X
翻译   杏仁斯嘉丽
翻译   沫沫
翻译   Lynn_宁
时间轴   纸袋P
时间轴  王者葱
后期   饿得慌
顾问   老杜
校对   草草
总监   草草
纸牌屋
第五季  第十三集
尊敬的国务卿女士
我谨辞去合众国总统职务
此致  弗兰西斯·J·安德伍德
罗梅洛议员呼吁在总统辞职后解散司法委员会
道格·斯坦普
抗议者在白宫草坪被击毙
弗兰西斯
罗梅洛议员
Oh, Congressman Romero,
我只是想走前最后看你一眼
I just wanted to see you one last time before I leave.
我觉得没什么好说的了
I don't believe there's anything left to be said.
我俩确实无话可说了
No, not between us. Not any longer.
我只是想谢谢
I just wanted to thank you for...
你的韧劲
your tenacity.
无论你想干什么  你都无法逍遥法外
Whatever you're up to, you won't get away with it.
也许我已经做到了
Maybe I already have.
委员会将继续工作
The committee will continue its work.
我们会建议司法部提出起诉
We'll recommend charges to DOJ.
罗谢尔
Rochelle.
多美的名字
Such a lovely name.
告诉我你有多么不想那名字上新闻
Tell me how much you don't want that to end up in the press.
然后解散这个委员会
And then shut this committee down.
你得无条件听我的
No deals.
总统先生  总统先生
Mr. President! Mr. President!
你怎么能这样
How could you?
-你怎么能不提前告诉我  -为了保护你
- How could you not warn me? - To protect you.
-我是要保护你  -你别碰我
- I was protecting you. - You should take your hands off me.
如果你觉得措手不及  我理解
No, look, I understand if you feel broadsided.
-我不在意什么感觉  弗兰西斯  -但听我说
- I don't care about feelings, Francis. - But listen to me...
克莱尔  听我说
Look, Claire, listen to me.
你让我把丑出尽了
You made me look absolutely ridiculous.
-毫无准备  稀里糊涂  -不  克莱尔
- Ill-prepared and ignorant. - No! Claire.
-我们有一条规则  弗兰西斯  -不
- We have one rule, Francis. - No,
-一条  -现在没了
- One rule.  - not anymore. Not anymore.
-没了  -如果我不知道你的想法
- We don't. - I cannot be your ally
就无法当你的盟友
if I don't know what you're thinking.
克莱尔  事情本会闹个没完
Listen, Claire. It would have never ended.
好吧  就算阻止了司法委员会
All right, fine, we got to stop judiciary,
其他委员会也会冒出来
but other committees would have sprung up,
一直指控我们
just to keep the charges going.
监管  军事  外事  情报等等委员会
Oversight, Armed Services, Foreign Affairs, Intelligence.
事情会没完没了的
It would have gone on and on.
-年复一年的  -我不管  弗兰西斯
- Years and - I don't care, Francis.
-调查  -你该跟我说的
- years of investigation. - You should have talked to me,
而不是像这样临时决定
instead of making a last-minute decision like this.
我没有
I didn't.
我制造了这混乱  好利用它
I created this confusion in order to take advantage of it.
所有事情都是计划好的
Everything that has happened... was planned.
何时开始的
Since when?
去极乐之地前
Since before Elysian Fields.
但我是在极乐之地猛然领悟到
But it was at Elysian Fields that it hit me.
我明白了
I saw it...
就像头顶上的灯泡亮了起来
almost like a light bulb going off above my head.
真正的权力在何处
Where does the real power lie?
就是权力背后的权力
The power behind the power.
克莱尔  我明白了
And I understood, Claire,
我们不能像过去那样思考行动
that we have to think and act differently than we ever have.
因为关键已经不在于谁住在白宫
Because it's no longer about who lives in the White House...
而在于谁拥有白宫
it's about who owns the White House.
这可是总统一职  政客还能爬多高
This is the presidency. How much higher can a politician go?
真正的权力不在这儿
The real power isn't here.
而在之外
It's beyond here.
超越了它  但仍要与之配合工作
It's above it, but still working in conjunction with it.
克莱尔  你我一直都在圈内
Look, Claire, you and I have always been on the inside.
被困在泡泡里
Trapped. In the bubble.
但从今往后
But going forward...
我在私营部门经营圈外
with my operating on the outside, in the private sector,
你在这里工作
and you working from here...
我们能一起拥有白宫
we can own this house together.
你不明白吗  这是我计划好的
Don't you see? I've designed this.
我想让你当总统
I wanted you to be the president.
我让你成为了总统
I've made you the president.
我该向你道谢吗
Am I supposed to say thank you?
不
No.
但你得赦免我  赦免我所有的罪行
But you will have to pardon me. Pardon me for all of my crimes.
作为总统  只有你才能这么做
As the president, you're the only one who can.
弗兰西斯  如果我这么做会被弹劾
Francis, I could be impeached if I do that.
不会的  戴维斯和厄舍
No, no. Look, Davis and Usher,
他们可以保护你
they're in a position to protect you.
-他们希望你成功  -世事难料  弗兰西斯
- They want you to succeed. - We can be sure of nothing, Francis.
道格的事
Everything going on with Doug,
白宫还有泄密者
the leak still in the White House...
不  那也是我
No, that was me, too.
-什么  -我就是泄密者
- What? - I'm the leak.
这几个月我一直在道格的帮助下
I've been feeding information to Tom Hammerschmidt
给汤姆·汉默施密特放料
for months with Doug's help.
这没道理  弗兰西斯
That doesn't make any sense, Francis.
克莱尔  如果你在别人之前扳倒自己
Claire, when you bring yourself down before someone else can,
你就能控制这个过程了
you control the way it happens.
只有这条路才能让我们来到此刻
This was the only path to get us to this moment
你和我  能够拥有一切
where you and I can own it all.
撤掉监控
Get rid of the surveillance.
抹除一切  停掉一切  你跟道格做的一切
Erase it. Shut everything down. Anything you and Doug were up to.
好  但是你得先赦免我
All right. But you have to pardon me first.
等时机合适  还要赦免道格
And, at the right time, Doug.
否则我们可能都要进监狱
Or we could both go to prison.
我杀了汤姆
I killed Tom.
我杀了汤姆·耶茨  他死了
I killed Tom Yates. He's dead.
我让马克处理掉了
And I had Mark clean it up.
所以这永远不会追查到我们
So it will never make its way back to us.
那我们都做了必须做的事
Well, then I guess we both did what we had to.
-你知道他要做这事吗  -不知道
- Did you know he was gonna do this? - No.
因为这很不好  克莱尔  这非常不好
Because this is bad, Claire. This is very... very bad.
天哪
My God!
你们两个怎么回事
What is it with you two?
-如果你在想什么  说...  -在我家里
- If there's something on your mind, say... - In my house?
你把他留在我家里了
You left him in my house?!
小声点  至少改变你的语气
Lower your voice, or at least change your tone.
你处理好了吗
Did you take care of it?
是的  那是我的工作
Yes, that's what I do.
那谢谢你  做得好
Then thank you, and well done.
现在我们回到眼前的事
Now let's get back to what's in front of us.
他想让你待在这里吗  克莱尔
Does he even want you to be here, Claire?
马克  拜托  我现在需要的是你的政治盘算
Mark, please. What I need right now is your political calculus.
他将你和我们所有人置于了为难的境地
He has put you, he has put all of us, in an impossible position.
你明白吗
You see that?
如果你不能正确处理这件事  就无法恢复了
If you don't handle this correctly, you do not recover from it.
这事关政府的持续运作
This is about continuity of government.
通知北约  通知各国领导人
Informing NATO, informing world leaders.
我们本该让大使们待命的
We should have had ambassadors on call.
参谋长联席会议  国家安全...
Joint Chiefs of Staff, the National Security...
连尼克松都那样做了
Even Nixon did that!
我准备好上交了
I'm ready to hand it over,
但是我要得到保证  不管怎样
but I want to be assured that no matter what,
麦卡伦之死不会牵连到我
Macallan's death is not related to me.
这可以办到
That can be taken care of.
-我要你手上我的东西  -好
- I want what you have of mine. - Okay.
会给你的
That's what you'll get.
我还要当幕僚长
And I want to be Chief of Staff.
我觉得这不是问题
Well, I don't think that's a problem.
很高兴你在提要求
I'm glad you're asking for what you want.
道格·斯坦普会为总统做任何事
Doug Stamper would do anything for the president.
他看到了佐伊·巴恩斯的威胁
He saw a threat in Zoe Barnes,
她跟总统有私情
who the president was involved with.
他就处理掉了
And he took care of it.
他不止一次地威胁过我的生命
He's threatened my life on numerous occasions.
-但是回到我的问题  -不  女士
- But to go back to my question... - No, ma'am.
我不认为总统知道道格在做什么
I don't think the president knew what Doug was up to.
完全不了解
Not at all.
汉默施密特先生
Mr. Hammerschmidt.
我想给你打电话来着
I've been meaning to call you.
肖恩
Sean.
你应该能看出来  我现在在这里工作
As you can tell, I work here now.
我现在跟你握手
I'm shaking your hand right now
是因为我崇尚社交礼仪
because I believe in social graces.
你迷失了
You're lost.
-我不这么认为  -不  你就是迷失了
- I don't think so. - No, you are.
不  我一点都没迷失
No, not at all.
这就是你想要的
This is what you wanted?
为腐败的政府和走向毁灭的总统卖命
A job in a corrupt administration? Presidency in ruin?
我是在白宫里面
I'm in the White House.
不是在外面  好奇着里面是什么样
Not out there, wondering what it's like in here.
不会很久的
Not for long.
你一旦进来了  就是进来了  这就是美国特色
Once you're in, you're in. It's the American way.
-斯坦普先生现在可以见你了  -谢谢
- Mr. Stamper will see you now. - Thank you.
抱歉让你久等了
Sorry to keep you waiting.
当我提出这次会面时  我不知道
When I asked for this meeting, I had no idea
总统今晚要签字辞职
the president would be signing his resignation this evening.
还有我  今天早上辞职
And I, this morning.
-我听说了传闻  -现在确定了
- I heard a rumor you might. - Now it's confirmed.
斯坦普先生
Mr. Stamper...
请说  你可以叫我道格
Yeah, please. You can call me Doug.
还是免了  毕竟这是正式采访
I'd rather not, for the sake of this interview.
希望你知道这不是私下谈话
I want you to know this will not be off the record,
或作为幕后消息
or on background.
我确实认识丽萨·威廉姆斯  几年前认识的
I do know Lisa Williams. I met her a couple years ago.
好的
Okay.
但在我们谈其他事之前
But before we get to anything else...
安德伍德总统
did President Underwood,
在还是议员时  是否杀害了佐伊·巴恩斯
when he was congressman, kill Zoe Barnes?
没有
No.
斯坦普先生
Mr. Stamper...
你是否杀害了佐伊·巴恩斯
did you kill Zoe Barnes?
我没准备好回答那个问题
I'm not prepared to answer that question.
你明白我可以白纸黑字写明你拒绝回答吧
You understand I can use your refusal in print.
明白
Yes.
佐伊死的那天  你是否在大教堂高地
Were you on the Cathedral Heights D.C. Metro platform
地铁站的站台上
the day of Zoe's death?
任何涉及佐伊·巴恩斯的问题
Any questions regarding Zoe Barnes,
你得去跟我的律师谈
you need to speak with my attorneys.
佐伊·巴恩斯是否用一部一次性手机
Did Zoe Barnes make a call to Francis Underwood
打给了时任议员的弗兰西斯·安德伍德
from a burner phone when he was congressman?
-你为什么要问我  -你为什么不回答
- Why would you ask me that? - Why won't you answer?
总统的手机几乎都是我在接
I almost always answer the president's phone.
电话  短信
Calls, texts...
你知道那些短信吗
Do you have any knowledge of those texts?
我没准备好作出评论
I'm not prepared to comment on that.
那么这次谈话到此为止
Then this conversation is over.
祝好
Have a good day.
最后一件事
One last thing.
你是否给我寄过两张生日贺卡
Did you send me two birthday cards?
没有
No.
[苏格兰盖尔语]
Slàinte mhath.
是苏格兰盖尔语  意思是"祝安康"
That's Scottish Gaelic. It means "Good health."
我父亲有点执迷
My father's kind of obsessed.
他将我们格雷森家的历史
And he traced our line of Graysons back to,
追溯到了16世纪左右
like, 16th century or something.
如果我们午休时需要喝一杯
Well, if we ever needed a drink in the middle of the day...
联邦检察官那边进展顺利
It went well with the US attorney.
真令人悲痛
It's tragic.
一想到道格做了什么  我们的心都碎了
Our hearts are just broken at the thought of what Doug did.
我不知道他怎么了
I don't know what happened to him.
可能到了某个时候...
I guess somewhere along the line...
他什么时候会宣布辞职
When will, uh, he be announcing his resignation?
-今天下午  -当然
- It's happening this afternoon. - Oh, of course.
赛斯  你也得辞职
And, Seth, you'll need to resign as well.
-我还以为  -我知道  但你想想
- I thought that, uh... - I know, but think about this.
我得建立我自己的团队  得公开进行
I need to establish my own team. Publicly.
不能回避
And there's no avoiding
目前你跟道格和弗兰西斯的关系有多紧密
how tied you and Doug are to Francis at this point.
这只是为了等一切烟消云散  仅此而已
So, it's really just waiting for the dust to settle. That's all.
怎么感觉像是你在告诉我
Why does it feel like you're telling me
我的职业生涯结束了  副总统女士
my career is over, Madam Vice President?
不  我只是说  你得先离开一阵子
No, I'm just saying, you just need to go away for a little while.
稍后我们会召你回来的
And we'll bring you back into the fold at a later date,
不用担心
and don't worry.
看看莉安  她也离开过  现在她回来了
Look at LeAnn. She left and now she's back.
我们以前一起喝过酒吗
Have we ever had a drink together?
从来没有
Never.
我想在您还是总统时  把这个交给您
I wanted to hand this to you while you were still president.
我带着沉重的心情接受了
I accept this with a heavy heart.
我昨天跟律师们开了一个战略会议
I had a strategy session with the attorneys yesterday.
希望他们好好对你了
I hope they're treating you well.
你知道
You know...
道格  现在起
Doug, we're not gonna be able
我们将有一阵子不能见面了
to see each other for some time now.
不如你拿点什么东西当纪念吧
So why don't you take something?
-不了  -没关系  随意挑吧
- No. - No, no. Go on. Take something.
任何东西  你想要什么都行  即便很小
Anything. Anything you want. Even if it's small.
一个你能握在手里
Something you can hold in your hand
让你回想起这里的东西  直到你回来
to remind you of this place... until you get back.
随便选吧
You go on.
离我的正式辞职只有几小时了
We're a few hours away from my official resignation...
而你还没答应赦免我
and you still have not agreed to pardon me.
如果你不
And if you don't,
我将不得不撤回辞职的决定
I will be forced to renege on that resignation.
那就太过分了
That would be outrageous.
我递交了签字辞呈  才算正式辞职
Well, it isn't official until I submit a signed letter.
这对你余下的总统任期有什么好处
And what would that do to the rest of your presidency?
还能剩下什么
What would be left of it?
克莱尔  如果你不同意
Claire, if you don't do it,
你可能就要与重罪犯是夫妻了
you're gonna risk being married to a felon.
如果我同意  那又置我于何地
And if I do, where does that leave me?
你现在真的想和我谈这个吗
Look, is this really the conversation you want to be having?
你给我设局  弗兰西斯
You've trapped me, Francis.
不  我不接受害了你的指责
No, I do not accept that I've done something to you.
我给你提供了一个机会
I have provided you with an opportunity.
你之前也说过  这就是你的终局
Now, you have said before, that this is your endgame.
眼下你的终极目标唾手可得
And now, your goal is within spitting distance
而你只看到了背叛  我不信
and all you see is betrayal? I don't buy it.
别再纠结我对你做了什么了
Stop talking about what I've done to you.
承认吧
Admit it.
这就是你想要的
This is what you want.
你愿意为之杀人
You were willing to kill for it.
那么克莱尔  接受吧
So, Claire, come and take it...
不然我就要收回了
before I take it back.
我们要挑选最合适的时机和地点
We'll find the most strategic time and place.
但我会特赦你  弗兰西斯
But I will pardon you, Francis.
为了国家利益  我们也应该解散委员会
For the good of the nation, we need to disband this committee,
把这一页翻过去
and put this behind us.
总统很可能撑不过听证会
The president most likely would not have survived the hearings.
你也可以说他是被迫辞职
You could argue that he had no choice but to resign.
但我们也不能否认他的证词引起很大反响
But we can't deny that his testimony struck a chord.
就算是这样
Well, that may be true.
那你  罗梅洛议员
But how is it that you, Congressman Romero,
他最主要的批评者  怎么转而支持他了呢
his biggest critic, are supporting him now?
历史
History.
今天结束时
By the end of the day,
我们国家会第一次有位女总统
the country will have its first woman president.
我一直支持有一位女性
Look, I've always been a supporter of the idea
能入主白宫
of a woman in the Oval Office.
但是说到底
But when all is said and done,
您应该清楚弗兰西斯·安德伍德
you do realize that Francis Underwood
今晚还是会在白宫过夜的吧
will still be sleeping in the White House tonight?
你不是该收拾东西了吗
Isn't this when you pack everything up?
至少带走个人物品
Or at least take the personal things?
我什么都不拿了
I'm not taking anything.
任你处置吧
You can do what you want with it.
-你什么时候见联邦检察官  -后天
- When do you meet with the US attorney? - Day after tomorrow.
我从没想过弗兰克·安德伍德会下台
I never thought that Frank Underwood would not be president.
真没想过
Not really.
你可以逃跑
You could just run away.
那我有什么好处
What does that get me?
你很擅长照顾自己
You're good at taking care of yourself.
真好笑
That's funny.
我希望你知道我关心你
Look, I want you to know that I care for you,
但恐怕我也帮不上你什么了
but I don't know how much I can be there.
我想就在这里坐一会儿
I think I'm gonna just sit here for a while.
嗯  坐吧
Yeah, you should.
副总统希望你在她宣誓就职之前
Uh, the vice president would like you to leave the White House
离开白宫
before she's sworn in.
她认为最好不要传出什么她就职时
She doesn't think it would be a good idea for word to get out
你还在白宫的消息
that you were here when it happened.
本人庄严宣誓  我必忠实执行
I do solemnly swear that I will faithfully execute
合众国总统职务
the office of President of the United States,
忠于职守  竭尽全力  恪守  维护
and will to the best of my ability preserve, protect
和捍卫合众国宪法
and defend the Constitution of the United States.
-愿上帝助我  -又是这熟悉的一幕
- So help me God. - Here we are again.
知道吗  如果你忽略盛大的仪式和场合
You know, if you ignore all the pomp and circumstance,
最反常的事就是我真的相信总统之位
the most perverse thing is I actually believe in the presidency.
其重要性
Its importance.
对世界的重大意义  哪怕只是象征性的
What it means around the world, even symbolically.
但我更相信权力  信它本身
But I believe in power even more. For its own sake.
戈尔·维达尔[作家]曾写道
Gore Vidal once wrote
权力的目的是权力
that power is an end to itself,
而夺取胜利的本能冲动
and the instinctive urge to prevail...
是人类最为重要的特性
the most important single human trait.
我总是告诉我自己  我做的一切都是为了她
I've always told myself that everything I did was for her.
但也许并不是  也许我更爱权力
But maybe it wasn't. Maybe I love power more.
为你  和你亲爱的人
For you, and for any dear to you,
我愿做任何事
I would do anything.
如果有幸  我的生涯中
If my career were of that better kind
有做出牺牲的机会或是能力
that there was any opportunity or capacity to sacrifice in it,
我愿抓住一切机会  为你和你亲爱的人牺牲
I would embrace any sacrifice for you and for those dear to you.
在宁静的时候  请记得我
Try to hold me in your mind, at some quiet times,
记得我这番热情而真挚的话
as ardent and sincere in this one thing.
那一天终会到来
The time will come,
那一天已经不远
the time will not be long in coming,
你将建立起新的关系
when new ties will be formed about you.
那关系将会更加温情而有力地把你
The ties that will bind you yet more tenderly and strongly
跟你悉心经营的家连结在一起
to the home you so adorn.
那是永远为你增光  令你幸福的最亲密的关系
The dearest ties that will ever grace and gladden you.
马内特小姐
Oh, Miss Manette,
等一个长得
when the little picture
和他幸福的父亲一样的小家伙仰起脸看你时
of a happy father's face looks up in yours...
晚上好
Good evening.
晚上好  女士们先生们  我叫肖恩·杰弗瑞斯
Good evening, ladies and gentlemen. My name is Sean Jeffries.
我是新新闻部副主任
I'm the new deputy director of communications.
赛斯去哪了
Where's Seth?
格雷森先生上台前被叫走了
Mr. Grayson got called away last minute,
所以我临时替代一下他
so I'm temporarily filling his shoes.
我不回答问题
I won't be taking any questions.
我要读一份拟好的声明
Instead, I'll be reading from a prepared statement.
几小时前
A few hours ago,
安德伍德总统
President Underwood resigned
辞去了美国总统一职
the office of President of the United States.
在有白宫人员参加的私密仪式上
And in a private ceremony attended by staff,
克莱尔·安德伍德总统宣誓就职
President Claire Underwood was sworn in.
即刻生效  她将担任
Effective immediately, she will be assuming the office
美国总统一职
of President of the United States.
稍后会具体公布将由
Details will be coming shortly on who will
-谁来接任  -你一定很为他骄傲
- be stepping into the office as - You must be so proud of him.
副总统
vice president.
弗兰西斯·安德伍德总统今天虽无法亲自前来
And while President Francis Underwood couldn't be here today...
三小时前进行了权力交接
Transfer of power happened three hours ago,
过程"私密而低调"
quote, "privately and quietly."
头版头条就是它了
And that's above the fold.
-司法部有什么消息吗  -还没有
- Anything from DOJ? - Nothing yet.
马克·厄舍没有正式头衔
No official title to him,
但权力交接是他主持的
but it's Mark Usher running the transition.
好  我们来看看谁进谁出
Okay. Let's find out who's in and who's out.
多米诺骨牌在不断倒下
The dominoes are falling.
-谁负责调查罗梅洛  -我
- Now, who's on Romero? - Here.
-我们想让议员公开发声  -好的
- We want the congressman on the record. - I've got it.
留着麦卡伦周末再爆料
And let's save Macallan for the weekend.
汤姆  道格·斯坦普怎么样了
Tom, where are we with Doug Stamper?
我得去核查点东西
There's, uh, something I need to check on.
头条网  消息网
Slugline, BuzzFeed,
全市一半的新闻渠道都等着这则大新闻呢
half the outlets in this city are ready to jump on this.
你跟他一对一谈过
You spoke to him. One on one.
-他没说是他干的  -他不用说
- He didn't actually say he did it. - He doesn't have to.
有人知道赛斯·格雷森对联邦检察官说了什么吗
Does anyone know what Seth Grayson said to the US attorney?
汤姆
Tom?
你写这届政府写了两年了
Two years you've been writing about this administration.
-机会来了  -我想继续追查而已
- This is it. - I want to follow up, that's all.
我看见一座美丽的城市
I see a beautiful city
和一个灿烂的民族从这深渊中升起
and a brilliant people rising from this abyss.
在他们争取真正的自由的奋斗中
And in their struggles to be truly free,
在他们的胜利与失败中
in their triumphs and defeats,
在未来的漫长岁月中
through long years to come,
我看见这一时代的邪恶和前一时代的邪恶
I see the evil of this time and of the previous time
前者是后者的自然结果
of which this is the natural birth,
逐渐赎去自己的罪孽  慢慢消失
gradually making expiation for itself and wearing out.
华盛顿时间今天凌晨三点左右
Surface-to-surface missiles delivered sarin
地对地沙林毒气导弹
at about three o'clock in the morning, our time.
莫斯科已经发出声明  谴责反政府军
Moscow has already issued a statement condemning the rebels
策划了这场苦肉计袭击
for orchestrating the attack on themselves.
-真是吗  -当然不是
- And did they? - Of course not.
佩特罗夫是想利用它发动正当空袭
Petrov will use this to justify air strikes.
我给你看张照片
I'd like to show you an image.
这张是路透社的
This one is coming out of Reuters.
我有预感  上午大多数媒体都会发这张
The feeling is most of the press will be using it by the a.m.
依我的经验
Experience tells me
这件事会回响个三五天
this will resonate for about three to five days...
也就给了我们机会
which gives us our window.
我们可以准备一份声明
Well, we can ready a statement.
出兵才是真正的声明
Troops on the ground is the statement.
不  我想等找到艾哈迈迪再行动
No, I don't want to do anything until we find Ahmadi's location.
我不确定这件事我们应该选择等待  总统女士
I'm not sure we should wait on this, Madam President.
我想提醒你发出最后通牒的
I'd like to remind you that it was this administration
正是这个政府
that introduced the ultimatum.
你该有所行动
You should act on it.
是  但我都没有像样的团队
Yes, but I barely have a team in place.
你可以用前总统的团队
Well, you can run it by the former president...
前总统就是前总统
The former president is just that.
机会就在眼前
An opportunity has presented itself.
而我想把握住机会
And I'm trying to take advantage of it.
-大家都在战况室了吗  -20分钟前都齐了
- Is everyone in the Situation Room? - As of 20 minutes ago.
时机不对
So, the timing is bad.
如果现在赦免他  会显得你跟他的罪行有关
If you pardon him now, you're associated with his crimes.
共和党人会咬着你不放
Republicans will have a field day.
我们需要掩护
We need some cover.
那就是抓捕艾哈迈迪
Well, that would be Ahmadi's capture.
合适的副总统对我们有好处
The right VP would help all this.
你有更多想法吗
Have you had any further thoughts?
最终名单没变
My short list is the same.
韦斯特维尔特  克拉克  克莱因
Westervelt, Clark, Klein.
克莱因最有可能
Klein would be the strongest bulwark
抵抗对你的弹劾
against calls for your impeachment.
-这是剜肉补疮  -补疮是关键
- Swallowing poison to stay alive. - Alive is good.
我觉得我受不了克莱因
I don't think I can stomach Klein.
他称我为贱人  不如克拉克
He called me a bitch. I prefer Clark.
告诉我  搬走尸体前
Tell me. Before you moved the body,
你帮他合上双眼了吗
were you able to close his eyes?
合上了
Yes.
我知道你很重视他的想法
Look... I know his opinion means a lot to you.
弗兰西斯
Francis.
但让他待在白宫  即便在东厢
But having him here, in the White House, even in the East Wing,
也会干扰我们处理事情
while we're trying to figure this out, it's hard.
总会有人暗示
At some point, someone is going to imply
仍是他在做决定
that he is still making the decisions.
那可不妙
That wouldn't be good.
-我会给她建议  她会想通的  -但愿吧
- I'll advise her. She'll come around. - I hope so.
叙利亚的事  如果她现在不行动
Because if she doesn't act now, when it comes to Syria,
她的总统位子就坐不稳
her presidency could be in danger.
你的未来也有变数
And your future in doubt.
别威胁我  戴维斯女士
Oh, don't threaten me, Ms. Davis.
我不威胁别人
I don't threaten.
我只是想尽量说清楚
I just try to remain as clear as possible.
你帮我做事  我也帮你做事
You offered me your services, and I offered you mine.
要知道
You know...
我比你早来  也会比你晚走
I was here before you and I'll be here after you.
即便如此  让我提醒你
And regardless of that, let me remind you...
没有比我更危险的东西
that nothing is more dangerous than me.
你现在得务实  戴维斯没说错
You need to be practical now. Davis isn't wrong.
我们已经想抓捕艾哈迈迪一年了  弗兰西斯
We've been trying to get our hands on Ahmadi for a year, Francis.
-她还没有实现  -没错  但关键不是她
- She hasn't delivered. - Yes, but this isn't about her.
而是你  还有第一次向全国发表讲话
This is about you and coming out with a strong message
传达出来的有力信息
in your first address to the nation.
关键是为你的任期定下基调
This is about setting the course for your presidency.
要强大  克莱尔
Be strong, Claire.
开战吧
Go to war.
但我需要你离开
But I need you to leave.
离开白宫
Leave the White House.
是  我懂
Yes, I see.
为了能成功赦免你  弗兰西斯
For this pardon to succeed, Francis,
我们得表现得有所疏远
we need to appear to be estranged.
这只是策略
I'm just being strategic.
你建议我去哪
And where do you suggest I go?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
海军天文台
The Naval Observatory?
我觉得副总统府邸还是太近了
I think the vice president's residence is still too close.
抱歉  我只是...
I'm sorry, I just...
我们不能让别人认为你还在干政
We can't have anyone think you're still involved in policy.
如果你动摇了
Look, if you're having second thoughts,
-你现在就该告诉我  -不
- you should tell me now. - No.
-我完全同意  -因为这可不是犹豫的时候
- No. I'm in full agreement. - 'Cause this is no time to hesitate.
我没在犹豫
I am not hesitating.
我只是觉得如果我们不妥当处理
I just believe if we don't play this correctly,
那对公众而言
as far as the public,
我的任期不过就是我俩苟且偷生
my term will be nothing but survival for both of us.
好吧
All right.
我希望你知道我会帮助你
I want you to know I'm here
如果你需要政策或其他事情的建议
if you need any advice on policy or anything else you might need.
谢谢你  我去睡了
Thank you. I'm going to bed.
没有人会像我一样爱你
No one will ever love you as much as I do.
我希望你知道
I hope you know that.
就像我知道没有人会像你一样爱我
Just as I know that no one will ever love me... like you.
"在陶瓷青蛙下面"
"Under the porcelain frog."
答案必须准确  包括大小写
The answers are case-sensitive and exact.
只有一次机会
You won't get a second chance.
-第二个问题  -我最喜欢的棒球运动员吗
- And the middle one? - My favorite baseball player?
"韦德·博格斯"  两个G
"Wade Boggs." Two G's.
最后一个
And the last?
"你在奥斯丁的酒店房间留了什么"
"What did you leave in that hotel room in Austin?"
我的枪在哪
Where is my gun?
给
Here you go.
你能给我什么保证
What guarantees do I have?
我把枪还给你了
I gave you your gun back.
但你为什么给他  我很好奇
But what made you give it to him? I'm curious.
我觉得他有危险
I thought he was in danger.
那你现在怎么觉得
And now you think what?
我想问的就是这个
That is what I'm asking.
只要我在  你会一直是本届政府的成员
As long as I'm around, you'll be a part of this administration.
我们都知道艾丹太多事
We both know too much about Aidan.
克莱尔知道你有多忠诚  我很确定
And Claire knows how loyal you are. I'm sure of it.
所以  你在奥斯丁的酒店房间留了什么
So, what did you leave in that hotel room in Austin?
一条手链
A bracelet.
真糟糕
That's too bad.
我终于看到了
You know, I finally got a look
麦卡伦留给哈维小姐的东西
at what Macallan passed on to Ms. Harvey.
你和你丈夫偷走了这场大选
I was shocked to realize the degree
程度之深  真是让我震惊了
to which you and your husband stole this election.
我得对你实话实说
I need to be honest with you.
我和他谈过
I've been in talks with him about
帮他发起一个基金会
helping him start a foundation of some kind.
换取对你的影响
In exchange for influence over you.
有意思
Interesting.
我想帮你度过这个过渡期
I'm trying to help you navigate this transition.
你对于我是什么人
Who are you to me?
你希望我是什么人
Who do you want me to be?
这个回答不好
That's not a good answer.
你是美国第一任女总统
You're the first woman President of the United States.
你忍了那么多  做了那么多牺牲和妥协
All you've had to swallow, the sacrifices, the compromises.
你会想要自我隔离
You're gonna want to isolate yourself.
不去相信任何人
Not trust anyone.
但你需要的正是这个
But that's exactly what you're gonna need.
需要有人告诉你真相
Someone to tell you what's what.
你就是这个人吗
And is that person you?
是吗
Is it?
我觉得不论我说什么都没法让你相信
I don't think there's anything i could say that would convince you
除非你已经感觉到了
if you don't already feel it.
戴维斯女士  你在要求我发动战争
Ms. Davis, you are asking me to start a war.
而你似乎只在你乐意时兑现诺言
And you seem to deliver on promises when it suits you.
所以  原谅我怀疑你的意图
So forgive me if I question your intentions.
我喜欢你
I like you.
我喜欢在你身边
I like being around you.
有时这让我失去了应有的效率
And sometimes that makes me less effective than I should be.
不论是否赦免你丈夫
Pardoning or not pardoning your husband,
他都是个不利因素
in either case, he's a liability.
如果治疗不当
If it's not treated properly...
你丈夫的肝脏随时可能衰竭
your husband's liver could fail him at any time.
这种事我做不了
It's not the kind of thing I could do.
但我可以找人  或者...
But I could find someone, or...
我...不知你是否知道
I... I don't know if you realize,
即便是胡蔓藤这种药物
but... even something like gelsemium
剂量太高时  也可能致命
can be lethal in higher doses.
我丈夫的健康状况没问题
My husband's health is just fine.
我会继续和他合作  跟随你的领导
I'll continue to work with him. Follow your lead.
这是我委托人的护照
Here's my client's passport.
有几件事我们要再重申一下
There's a few things we want to go over.
还没重申过的吗
That we haven't already?
我必须确定  你们带他出去时不戴手铐
No cuffs, when you walk him out of here. I need to be sure.
拜托  詹姆斯  我们不会这么干的
Oh, come on, James, we aren't gonna play that on this.
你有些很够意思的朋友  斯坦普先生
You have some very good friends, Mr. Stamper,
没让媒体报道这件事
to keep the press out of this.
你会像个绅士一样走出去
You will walk out of here like a gentleman.
我们要他12小时内面见法官
We want him in front of the judge within 12 hours.
我们还不知道是否会起诉他
We don't even know if we're gonna charge him yet.
是我做的
I did it.
继续吧
Let's get going.
你在她的内阁里有什么人
Who do you have on her cabinet?
现在还只是建议
Right now, they're just suggestions.
拜托  我们都知道这是怎么回事
Oh, come on. We both know how this works.
你已经做了决定
You've already made your choices.
如果没有  那就是你没本事
You wouldn't be worth your salt if you hadn't.
我只是希望你先让我过目一下
I just want you to run them by me first.
我能让这个过渡很轻松  也能给你制造麻烦
Look, I can make this transition easy for you or not.
给你一句忠告
And a word of advice.
她会需要
She's gonna need some
桌子那边坐着一些友好的面孔
friendly faces looking at her across that table.
会有一些人...
There'll be a few...
按要求微笑的
who will smile as required.
你看看这个
Would you look at this?
都是前特种部队的
Both Special Forces. Former.
他们知道如何忘记  所以你不必担心
They know how to forget, so you don't have to worry about them.
尸体呢
And the body?
处理好了
It's on ice.
我刚刚和纳泽取得了联系
I just made contact with Nasser.
我们已经拿到了艾哈迈迪的位置
We have secured the location of Ahmadi.
我来召集队伍
I'll assemble the team.
我已经给戴尔海军上将打过电话了
I called Admiral Dale already.
那我们现在得做些决定
So we have some decisions to make.
一旦我们派部队过去
Once we have troops on the ground,
我们需要仔细看一下
we'll need to take a close look
我们为你的内阁考虑的人选
at who we're considering for your cabinet.
你身边需要有战时经验的团队
You'll need a team around you with wartime experience.
我有些建议  已经传达给马克了
I have some suggestions I've passed on to Mark.
我认为中情局的副局长  玛茜·西格森
I think Deputy Director of the CIA, Marcy Siegerson,
会是极佳的国务卿人选
would make a terrific Secretary of State.
我很容易与其协调联系
Someone I could easily liaison with.
我还希望
Well, I was hoping that
你会以某种形式加入我的内阁
you would be on my cabinet, in some capacity.
我会在圈外工作
I'll be operating out of the region.
那是我的强项
It's where my strength lies.
我们有更好的能够接手的人选
There are better people who can take it from here,
能够在大后方给你建议
advise you on the home front.
哈维小姐  莉安  我们需要调动一下你的职位
And Ms. Harvey, LeAnn, we need to move you.
当然只是暂时的
Uh, just for now, of course.
我以为...
It was my understanding that...
现在一个更老道的幕僚长
Right now a more seasoned Chief of Staff
会向国会和国家传递
would send a strong message
强有力的信息  目前是这样
to the Congress and to the nation. For now.
她会做的  她会派部队过去
She'll do it. She'll send in the troops.
明天下午我就会到迪拜了
I'll be in Dubai by tomorrow afternoon.
我们的交易依旧不变
And our deal stays in place.
等一下
Yeah, hold on a second.
-准备好了吗  -好了
- Ready?  - Go ahead.
是的  哈维女士拿回了她的枪
Yes. Ms. Harvey has her gun back.
麦卡伦的档案在总统那里
Macallan's files are with the president.
任何能把你和选举联系起来的有力证据...
Any hard evidence connecting you to the election...
都在她手上
is in her hands.
那么莉安的工作结束了
Then LeAnn's job is done.
如果你还有什么要说的  现在是时候了
If you have anything to say, now is the time.
你觉得发生了什么
What do you think happened?
我更希望你来告诉我
I'd prefer you tell me that.
迁就我吧  是你要求见面的
Humor me. You asked for this meeting.
你觉得发生了什么
What do you think happened?
我相信佐伊·巴恩斯当时在调查
I believe Zoe Barnes was investigating
你和瑞秋·波斯纳的关系
a relationship you were having with Rachel Posner.
不知怎么的  那会危及到
And somehow, that knowledge would endanger
弗兰西斯·安德伍德
Francis Underwood,
那个你会为其赴汤蹈火的人
who you would do anything for.
但是有人想过佐伊·巴恩斯的生命吗
But did anyone think about the life of Zoe Barnes?
你觉得你能抹去一些东西
You know, you think you can erase something.
然后你发现那是不可能的
Then you find out that's not possible.
汤姆  我的律师根本不想让我和你交谈
Tom, my attorneys didn't even want me to speak with you.
抱歉  没什么好说的了
I'm sorry, there's just nothing more to say here.
我不知道瑞秋·波斯纳怎么了
I don't know what happened to Rachel Posner.
但是我不相信是你杀了佐伊·巴恩斯
But I don't believe you killed Zoe Barnes.
录像里的是你吗
Is this you in this video?
看起来像是我
Looks like me.
我仔细思考了很久  弗兰西斯
I've thought long and hard, Francis.
几乎没睡
Barely slept.
这份工作就是这样
That's the job.
我准备派部队过去
I'm going to send in troops.
我明晚就会宣布
I'll be announcing it tomorrow night.
我觉得你做了正确的事
I think you're doing the right thing.
你讨厌这儿吗
Do you hate it here?
你知道的  我不喜欢宾馆
Oh, you know I don't like hotels.
看着像家  但只是提醒你并不在家
An approximation of home just to remind you you're not there.
我们不是有家的人
Well, we don't live in a home.
我们有一座白宫  借来暂住
We live in a house, borrowed and temporary.
你的眼睛里有什么  有种眼神
Something in your eye. A look.
不一样了
It's changed.
你和我  现在是一样的了
We're the same now, you and I.
-怎么说  -你明白的
- How so? - You know how.
我很久没让我自己感到惊奇了
It's been a long time since I surprised myself.
你会恢复的
You'll recover.
你是世界上权力最大的女人  克莱尔
You're the most powerful woman in the world, Claire.
任何慰藉都难与匹敌
Comfort pales by comparison.
我会在宣布出兵之后宣布这条消息
I'll announce it during the speech, after the troops.
将全面无条件地赦免
A full and unconditional pardon...
弗兰西斯·安德伍德在担任美国总统期间
for Francis Underwood and any crimes he might have committed
可能犯下的任何罪行
against the United States while president.
我很高兴知道这一点
I'm glad to hear that.
我从没动摇过  我只是需要考虑一下方式
It was never in doubt. I just needed to think about how.
那这个安排要维持多久
So how long does this arrangement last?
暂时先这样吧
For the time being.
我们是怎么到这一步的  弗兰西斯
How did we get here, Francis?
别纠结了  已经过去了
Oh, let it go. It's done.
对了  再给你个建议
Oh, and one word of advice.
不管厄舍向你推荐谁做副总统
Whomever Usher offers up to you as vice president,
这个人就是你真正应该小心的人
that's the person that you're really gonna have to watch.
我应付不了的人  我是不会选的
I won't choose anyone I can't manage.
在楼的西南角  继续观察
Southwest corner of the building. Maintain visual.
收到
Copy that.
扔雷
Frag out!
艾哈迈迪在那儿  我看到艾哈迈迪了
There's Ahmadi. I have visual on Ahmadi.
-我看到他了  -冲  开火
- I see him. - Go, go! Fire!
我犯了个大错
I made a terrible mistake.
你做了什么
What did you do?
我都不知道我在做什么  我
I don't even know what I'm doing here. I, uh...
早上我开着车就出来了  我怕了
This morning I started driving. I... I got scared.
总之我正往回赶  我能去见你吗
Anyway, I'm on my way back. Can I come see you?
当然
Yes, please.
有时候看电影  你并不一定要看到最后
Sometimes you don't have to watch the whole movie
才知道结局
to know how it ends.
两党对演讲的反应应该会都不错
The speech is gonna play well with both parties.
和共和党人谈得怎么样了
Where are we with the Republicans?
关于你的内阁  我们正在交换名单
Trading names when it comes to your cabinet.
选了几个将军  这会有利
We have our generals, which is good.
有几个是公司出身  圈外人
Some corporate types, outsiders.
让你看着像个打破陈规的人
Make you seem like a renegade.
公司  从哪来的
Corporate, from where?
大多数是石油和银行业  也有搞技术的
Oil, banking, mostly. Some tech.
再掺几个特区的长期议员
Occasional D.C. lifer sprinkled into the mix
好让你的内阁按时开工
to make sure the trains run on time.
我在看副总统的名单
I was going over our list for vice president.
等等
Yeah. Hold on.
这可能有点意外
this will seem unexpected,
但是我问过的许多人都说我最合适
but a lot of the people I spoke to suggested me.
可你不是政客
You're not a politician.
没错
Exactly.
但我可以守在你身边
But I could be by your side.
这样国会两院大多数人都伤不到我们
Most of the Hill and the Senate would not come near us.
我会考虑的
I'll take it into consideration.
不能考虑了  你需要我
It's beyond that. You'll need me.
什么
Excuse me?
我能帮你
I can help. Look...
只有这样才能保住你的位子
It is the way to keep you in power.
和你的秘密
And keep your secrets.
晚上好
Good evening.
我在此向全体美国人民和全世界郑重宣布
I'm here to report to the American people and the world
在今天上午
that early this morning,
特种部队击毙了哈里发国恐怖分子
Special Forces killed the ICO terrorist
艾哈迈德·艾哈迈迪
Ahmed Al Ahmadi.
我们干掉他了
We got him.
我们消灭他了
在每一位男女总统任职期间
Now, there comes a time in every president's tenure
他们总会面临这么一个问题  就是要不要
when he or she must face the question of whether or not
派遣美国年轻人上阵杀敌
to send young American soldiers into harm's way.
对我而言
In my case...
我上任之初  就要面对这个难题了
that time has fallen within the very first days of my presidency.
俄罗斯总统维克多·佩特罗夫与中国合谋
Russian President Viktor Petrov collaborated with the Chinese
试图在南极洲非法开采石油
on illegal oil exploration in Antarctica.
最近我们又了解到  他已派出军队
Recently, we have learned that he has sent troops
与叙利亚当局并肩作战
to fight alongside the Syrian regime,
协助他们毁灭叙利亚国家
assisting them in the destruction of the Syrian nation.
政府军使用化学武器攻击自己的人民
These forces are using chemical weapons on their own people,
折磨异议人士
torturing the opposition,
让全国绝大多数人口忍饥挨饿
and starving huge segments of the population.
叙利亚人民已饱受战乱之苦
The Syrians are a people besieged.
不要再让他们被遗忘了
Let them not also be forgotten.
我们将怒火转化成行动的时机已经到来
The time has come for our outrage to be turned into action.
五个月前  我丈夫
Five months ago, my husband
曾向众议院发出呼吁
addressed the House of Representatives
要求他们向哈里发国宣战
and asked them to declare war on ICO.
国会让他失望了
Congress failed him.
国会让人民失望了
Congress failed you.
哈里发国极端分子图谋让我们的民主和国家
ICO extremists want democracy and America itself
轰然崩塌
to die a fiery death.
我们决不能让他们得逞
We cannot allow that to happen.
我们不能再等待国会了
We can't wait for Congress any longer.
我们给国会的机会已经够多了
We gave Congress every chance.
她是不打算说了
She isn't going to say it.
历史在评判每一位领袖  每一位总统的时候
Now, history judges every leader, every president,
都要看他或她是怎么对待自己的人民的
by how he or she treats his or her own people.
一个悍然攻击医院  难民营
A regime that would target hospitals, refugee camps,
学校和救济车队
schools or bread lines
只为了自保的政权  必须受到惩罚
in order to retain power must be confronted.
而身为国家领袖  却牺牲
A leader that would sacrifice
自己人民的幸福安康
the physical and emotional well-being of his citizens,
视人民如棋子筹码
that would treat his people as pawns,
就为了保住自己的权力
just to stay in power? Well...
这样的领袖必须下台
that leader needs to be stopped.
如果她不赦免我
If she doesn't pardon me...
我就杀了她
I'll kill her.
谢谢你们  上帝保佑我们伟大的国家
Thank you and God bless this great country.
电话已经涌进来了
Well, the calls are coming in already.
讲得好  今晚对你非常有利
Well done. This'll be a good night for you.
莫斯科那边还没有动静
Nothing from Moscow yet.
现在我想自己待一会儿
Right now I just need some time to myself.
你认识汤姆·耶茨吗
Do you know Tom Yates?
不熟  怎么了
Not personally. Why?
他有段时间没出现了
He hasn't been around in a while.
没事  算了
I don't know, forget it.
怎么了
What?
我一直在联系他  而他通常都回电话的
I've been calling him. And he usually answers.
我们要正义  我们要和平
We demand justice, we demand peace!
中东不要再打仗
No more war in the Middle East!
我们要正义  我们要和平
We demand justice, we demand peace!
中东不要再打仗
No more war in the Middle East!
我们要正义  我们要和平
We demand justice, we demand peace!
中东不要再打仗
No more war in the Middle East!
我们要正义  我们要和平
We demand justice, we demand peace...
白宫外爆发的反战示威游行
The anti- war demonstrations outside the White House
终于出了状况
finally got out of hand.
这里是莉安·哈维  请留言
You've reached LeAnn Harvey. Please leave a message.
一名抗议者翻过围栏
One of the protesters made his way over the gates.
在穿越白宫草坪的时候
As he was running across the White House lawn,
被赶来的特勤局特工包围
Secret Service agents moved in,
该名抗议者不幸被击毙
tragically shooting and killing the man.
这里是莉安·哈维  请留言
You've reached LeAnn Harvey. Please leave a message.
你在哪呢
Hey, where are you?
抱歉  女士  今晚是不行了
I'm sorry, ma'am, it's just not possible tonight.
我们无法确保跑步路线安全
We can't secure the run.
目前威胁等级太高了
The level of threat at this point is just too high.
-好的  谢谢你  -好的  女士
- Okay. Thank you. - Yes, ma'am.
该我了
My turn.
在过去几年中  美国对叙利亚的政策一直是外交事务的中心
而奥巴马和特朗普两任总统在这一事务中采取了截然不同的立场
2012年8月20日  奥巴马宣布"阿萨德政权如果使用化武便越过了'红线'"
2013年8月21日  媒体报道叙利亚境内大量平民遭到化武袭击
1429人罹难  包括426名儿童
全世界都以为奥巴马将对叙动武  美军军舰也部署完毕
但奥巴马临时改了主意  决定暂停武装打击计划  而寻求国会授权
最终不了了之  许多评论认为  此后普京在东欧放手东扩
也是觉得奥巴马外交上比较软弱  不会干涉克里姆林宫的行为
特朗普上任后  也遇到了阿萨德使用化武的事件
由于竞选时他反对过度干预国际事务  所以白宫虽发表了严厉声明
但媒体和美国公众  都没预料到特朗普真的会有决心进行武力打击
4月6日晚  白宫和五角大楼向媒体宣布
特朗普下令让部署在地中海的两艘美国海军军舰
向叙利亚政府军的一个空军基地  发射了60枚战斧导弹
摧毁了该基地的一些设施和战斗机
特朗普上任后  屡屡受到批评  媒体也多次爆出他的丑闻
但叙利亚打击后  不仅参众两院的民主党领袖都公开发表声明
对此举表示肯定和认可  媒体也破天荒地交口称赞
打击叙利亚成了特朗普总统生涯中  迄今为止最闪光的时刻